<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dan Bulwinkle</title>
    <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dan Bulwinkle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dan.bulwinkle.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Top Bitcoin</title>
      <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/you-cant-top-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/you-cant-top-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>Bitcoin has endured over a decade, and contenders are constantly being deployed. Why is it the best cryptocurrency? Here I review cash, gold, mobile, and other decentralized platforms and how they compare with Bitcoin. I consider myself a crypto altruist; I don&amp;rsquo;t subscribe to any sort of maximalism of any cryptocurrency. I want to see everyone have access to this technology regardless of the particular implementation, so long as it is entirely open source and has been peer reviewed by computer scientists1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grocery &amp; Meal Delivery</title>
      <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/grocery-and-meal-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/grocery-and-meal-delivery/</guid>
      <description>Why Don’t Grocery Delivery Services Have Inventory? I still go to the grocery store in part for the experience and the discovery process. Often times, however, I’ve wished I could just skip the store and have the groceries appear within a day. The problem with that is then I need to sign up for some delivery service and still spend time paging through an app to find dozens of necessities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperloop May Create New Cities</title>
      <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/hyperloop-may-create-new-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/hyperloop-may-create-new-cities/</guid>
      <description>City Planning and Real Estate Markets May Become Vastly Different If Hyperloop Succeeds Hyperloop concept from the original SpaceX white paper.Were I to create a hyperloop company I may call it R-Loop to emphasize keeping out the hype. If I was lucky maybe one day it would be known simply as “The R” just as elevated trains in Philly and Chicago are known as “The El.”
It’s been just a couple years since two major hyperloop companies have been in existence and the outlook is dubious.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>