
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
   <title>Series on Dan Bulwinkle</title>
   <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/series/</link>
   <description>Recent content in Series on Dan Bulwinkle</description>
   <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
   
       <atom:link href="https://dan.bulwinkle.net/series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
   
     <item>
       <title>The Best CEOs Respond</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/the-best-ceos-respond/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/the-best-ceos-respond/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 0.95&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin:auto;text-align:center&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/img/moms-organic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mom&#39;s Organic Paper Bag&#34;&gt;    *The CEO of Mom&#39;s Organic asking for feedback*&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CEO of a company is responsible for 3 things: the vision of the company, the talent, and cash flow. The latter two are largely affected by the vision. Without a strong vision the company may deteriorate into an unkempt invalid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are different degrees of visionaries. Many people tend to think of Steve Jobs when they think of the quintessentialvisionary. It&amp;rsquo;s eye opening to think that he was 50 when the iPhone was developed and he spent 12 years working on NeXT. He had over 30 years working alongside other brilliant people before developing the product that would catapult Apple into the multi-trillion dollar company it is today. Steve responded to customers:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin:auto;text-align:center&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/img/steve-jobs-email.png&#34; alt=&#34;An Email Response from Steve Jobs&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve sent a lot of emails to a variety of CEOs. I try to keep it short. A few years ago I sent Tim Cook a list of items, including one that prevented me from buying things due to the nature of how Apple handles credit cards&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Not only was there zero response, but I believe that issue persists today&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a handful of CEOs who do respond. Elliot Noss at Tucows responded both times I emailed, Dane Jasper at Sonic responded, and I got a lengthy response from someone on Jeff Bezos&amp;rsquo;s team. Amazon has dubious business practices, but the thing that they continue to get right (generally) is customer happiness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A natural argument is that CEOs are too busy to respond. One of the first high profile emails I sent was to Douglas Hofstadter and within a day or two I received a thoughtful email&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Do you think he has more important things to do than send a student a thoughtful letter?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The very idea that a CEO is too busy to respond to an email contradicts the fact that they should be spendinga good amount of time revising and extending the vision of the company. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen in a vacuum. Some people can see all of the cracks in the world, things that need to be fixed, solutions to fix them; there isn&amp;rsquo;t a single CEO who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t benefit from feedback from smart employees and customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CEOs should &amp;ndash; at the very least &amp;ndash; acknowledge their loyal customer. A simple &amp;ldquo;noted!&amp;rdquo; would do. They could forward the email to their executive team. In terms of productivity, they could arrange their email client such that it is a simple click to send the email into a folder which has a cron job waiting to ferry all of the emails to that team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not because Apple failed to implement most of the items on my list&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m no longer interested in being an Apple customer. It&amp;rsquo;s not because Elon Musk didn&amp;rsquo;t take action on the terrible user interface update for the radio controls&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m no longer interested in being a Tesla customer. It&amp;rsquo;s that there is little evidence that these CEOs have a vision and care about the company. They are riding on a cash cow that will soon deflate, but it&amp;rsquo;s the kind of situation that they won&amp;rsquo;t realize it until it&amp;rsquo;s too late. CEOs should be focused on the vision of the company. Talent and cash flow will follow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is convoluted and a testament to the complexity of Apple&amp;rsquo;s code base. But importantly Apple lost some amount of revenue but it is unclear how much, because how many other people have this issue?&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;People point to the massive growth in market capitalization as evidence the CEO is doing an excellent job, but in my opinion some CEOs just get on the flywheel at the right time.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bit off topic: I never emailed Paul Graham, but I did approach him at Startup School, and not only did he engage with me, but &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; was the one to end the conversation. While Michael Seibel is a responder of emails, Paul Graham should probably run Y Combinator.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple did fix the keyboard issue. I guess you have to create a particular mob for them to really listen.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tesla used to have a matrix for radio stations. Now it is an array which you have to scroll over, and after 5 seconds it scrolls back to the beginning for some reason?? Talent follows vision.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Autocomplete Selections Should Confirm with User</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/autocomplete/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/autocomplete/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;One UX issue that I run into more often than I&amp;rsquo;d like: when you type in a text box and a list or drop down appears and you tap on it immediately, only to learn that between the milliseconds that your brain executed the tap and your fingers touched the screen a new item replaced your intended target.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes this is a more benign environment where you are searching for something and after you type a few letters what you want appears, but you managed to type another letter and the results are changed due to network delay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to stray from the topic; however, I must point out that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this behavior pervasively in advertising. I first noticed it back in the early 2010s when using Meebo probably just before Google acquired it. You&amp;rsquo;d go to type a message in response to one someone sent and, surprise!, the spot where you were about to tap to focus the input box became an ad, pushing the input box higher in the interface. It seemed too well timed to be just a coincidence. Today I see this exact kind of behavior with Amazon, though it seems they are starting to transition to just making every result an ad so no need to trick you into clicking. Sadly I&amp;rsquo;ve even seen this with DuckDuckGo, eroding my trust in that company&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. What I can&amp;rsquo;t fathom is how the engineers behind these platforms let it happen. They must know what they are doing. Or, if you are a fraud investigator and search on Amazon and accidentally click one of these ads do you say to yourself, &amp;ldquo;Haha! I was fooled again!&amp;rdquo; The advertisers meanwhile don&amp;rsquo;t seem to care either, because revenue &amp;gt; cost of marketing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transitioning back to the crux of my post: there&amp;rsquo;s no technical reason for this! If you are planning to asynchronously return some kind of result in addition to your server-side result, it&amp;rsquo;s obvious that you can put a placeholder in your template. The contents of the placeholder can be up to your imagination: &amp;ldquo;Our valued sponsors have a result just for you.&amp;rdquo; It may be more effective to humanize the results than just treating the user as a sucker. &amp;ldquo;Got you, fool! Now pay me $8.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another way to deal with this, in the case of results in apps with search/dropdown combos without monetization incentives, is to calculate the time it takes between the last result populated and the newly invalidated list. In fact, use the same UX exploit that seemed to be happening with Meebo but display a dialog asking the user if they meant the previous result, current result, or something else. That this would only happen in circumstances where there was incongruity between the user&amp;rsquo;s input and the lagged result means it would be infrequent. Empirically it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen often, but when it does it can be obnoxious and cause more grief than a simple confirmation dialog box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 0.95&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, this just happened to me while using DDG yesterday.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Automate Hotels</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/automate-hotels/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/automate-hotels/</guid>
       <description>&lt;div style=&#34;margin:auto;text-align:center;padding-bottom:20px&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/img/hotellobby.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A Hotel Lobby&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Hotel Lobby&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 0.95&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly review some issues with the hotel experience, though I imagine they are evident to most people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An obvious issue is check-in. It&amp;rsquo;s unclear why this process is so time-consuming. I know there areapps that allow you to check in and use your phone as a key (which sometimes fails to workaccording to various hotel reviews), so let&amp;rsquo;s simply consider a hotel without thiscapability. You have to say your name, they sometimes ask for more info, ID, credit card, andthe process can take 10-20 minutes. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of time for something that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly add to the experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dcurtis&#34;&gt;Dustin Curtis&lt;/a&gt; has probably stayed at over a thousand hotels.I was surprised to learn he uses hotels.com and sometimesHotelTonight&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Discovery, it seems, is still a problem. At the time Dustin wrote this hotels.comhadn&amp;rsquo;t updated its interface in 20 years. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t broken. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what they didbut since the update a few years ago there have been various issues like the map does not display all thehotels and filters do not produce correct results. Hipmunk was pretty solid early on andsomehow that fizzled out. Hotels Tonight works great for narrow use cases. Most of the rest of the websites are half-baked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hotels are commodities. Not long ago I stayed at a hotel in Colorado and loved it,so I booked the same brand in Indiana and it was like crossing the railroad tracks.For that reason I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be loyal to a brand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever been to New York, hotels typically partner with a garage. Oftenthis isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem, but it can be a bottleneck and I&amp;rsquo;ve definitely waitedquite some time for the valet to return with the car.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few other issues with hotels like new ones tend to be poorly built and I have yet to see a hotel luxuryor not that has iron clad blackout blinds, but those issues are beyond the scope of &amp;ldquo;automate hotels.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-solution&#34;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automate all the things!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Of course it isn’t. Hospitality is about making people feel human and enjoying it.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; dustin curtis (@dcurtis) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dcurtis/status/1217076990148255744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 14, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, ok, automate &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the things. New York has a parking garage called AutoMotion. You approach the garage and drive your car onto a lift. After you get out you put in a credit card and get a receipt with which to retrieve your car. The car is then whisked into the garage using a robotic system. The price is market, but no tipping and a fairly predictable amount of time for retrieving your car. There are only a handful of these, and they seemed to stagnate not long after their debut more than 10 years ago. It works and should be the norm in any new construction not only in New York but everywhere it any city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Checking into a hotel should require nothing more than flashing your ID. What reason is there &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to prepare your key cardahead of time? Why so much typing at the computer? Indeed, there are some hotels with key card kiosks. Misunderstandings like forgetting to inform the hotel you have a pet shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be more than a small percentage of cases. I see no reason why it should take any longer than 2 minutes to check in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few other things that could be done to modernize the hotel experience. Why is it that you get assigned a random room? Every room should be set at market rate. Few hotels have decent soundproofing in the cavity between the floor and the ceiling, and if you are on vacation the last thing you want is to hear the person upstairs on a business trip getting ready at 6am. On that note, hotels should allow patrons to submit their plans to an automated system that helps themidentify where other people like them are going to be. Do you want to be in a room next to someone smoking on the balcony?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The point is, hotels could do better and enable a &lt;em&gt;predictable&lt;/em&gt; experience. Automation can help quite a bit here, but hotelexecutives need to secure the fundamentals. It seems like low hanging fruit if someone wants to start a hotel.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/pt-br/@ozzzyphotos?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Oswald Elsaboath&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/hotel-lobby?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m fairly certain this was a tweet, likely deleted&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dustin Curtis wanted to do this &amp;ndash; I wish he would!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Government Should Incentivize High Performance Home Builders</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/government-should-incentivize-green-builders/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/government-should-incentivize-green-builders/</guid>
       <description>&lt;div style=&#34;margin:auto;text-align:center;padding-bottom:20px&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/img/passivehouse.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Passive House in Brooklyn c. 2013&#34;&gt;  &lt;i&gt;Passive House in Brooklyn. Photo by Sam McAfee.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 0.92&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the US, new homes built today vary by the standards set by local governments. Standards may include specificeffective R-values for walls of the building envelope and usually a larger effective R-value for the roof. This,however, is not ideal because leaks can occur through cracks, the concrete slab, and thermal bridging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thermal bridging occurs when you have a low R-value item like lumber that directly connects the interior with the exterior of the envelope. There are techniques to eliminate thermal bridging like using raised trusses for the roof or putting insulation on the exterior of the house. Concrete slabs can be insulated using structural foam, and you can create an air-tight house by tapingand caulking all cracks and holes including those created by the trades that work on the interior&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue is that builders have almost no incentive to take these extra steps. In some markets, it can distinguish a home, but most people apparently are happy with basic new construction. Further, homes are being built with more square footage. In some markets 3000-4000 square foot new homes just 10 years ago was standard, and today it is more like 5000-6000 square feet. Finishing an attic and a basement costs less since those structures are there anyway, so this helps margins. But do newer generations want such a large footprint? Is it necessary?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People informed about health and environmental effects of natural gas are looking away from gas stoves and toward induction stoves. The topic of the environment has gone from recycling cans to actively tracking one&amp;rsquo;s carbon production. It&amp;rsquo;s unclear to what extent, though. If a builder created two homes next to each other, one 5200 square feet with standard construction practices, while the other was 4000 square feet using high performance building techniques and both were offered at the same price, which would be coveted by the 30-something home buyer?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to know the answer because building a speculative high performance home is risky in most markets. San Francisco and Boston have not only high land costs, but building a home that isn&amp;rsquo;t high performance can be anywhere from $350-$450 a square foot. High performance homes that aim for passive house or net zero energy usage can add 10% or more to the cost. Only if builders start seeing high custom home demand for net zero features will we start to see more speculative homes being built this way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not enough because there are people who don&amp;rsquo;t have the wealth to build a custom home nor buy a new home. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to recognize the home as an investment in future energy costs. Utility costs are on the rise, and not by a trivial amount or an amount keeping pace with inflation, but as much as 50%&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Even if carbon footprint isn&amp;rsquo;t on someone&amp;rsquo;s mind, rising energy costs should be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Normally I opt for market solutions to most problems. People seem to think government can play a dominant role in ceasing or reversing climate change, but that ship sailed 20 or 30 years ago. Climate change needs a beast of a solution, or a lot of little solutions that represent such a force of nature to reverse carbon emissions. Market forces at work here include companies that brag about negative emissions. I suspect we&amp;rsquo;ll see some unimaginable advances in the coming years thanks to the expectation that corporations not only claim zero emissions, but actively invest in carbon dioxide removal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; government do, then? Make high performance homes a standard. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean forcing builders to do it, but incentivizing them to do it and then high performance homes will be expected by the market. The same applies to retrofitting existing homes with net zero elements&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system could work like this: if the average new home is closing in on $500,000, then it might cost $50,000 to make it high performance: triple pane windows, extra thick insulation, insulated slab, and an air change per hour rate of 1.0 or less. The builder gets reimbursed for these costs plus a 10-20% fee. The government could amortize the cost over the course of 50 years. In this example it might be $100 a month, which is about the average cost of heating alone in the US&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Having a high performance home means heating and cooling require very little energy since the home prevents air from escaping (or entering) except using an energy recovery ventilator&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to keep the air fresh with minimal energy loss. Ancilliary benefits include comfortable atmosphere and allergen-reduced air. Overall, this would be a win for the homeowner, the builder, and society at large (government).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How the system is implemented is open to interpretation. That partly depends on the philosophy of the nature of government sovereign currency. It seems since 2010 there has been more adoption of Modern Monetary Theory as the idea of &amp;ldquo;current generation paying interest, future generation pays off debt&amp;rdquo; seems untenable. In terms of inflation, I don&amp;rsquo;t think there is a material supply issue but instead a trade worker constraint. For the repayment, maybe there is a third party that manages the implmentation, a bond system, or traditional IRS tax-oriented system. The claim of 10% is also for illustrative purposes: it could be less, especially as standards increase and environmentally minded buyers come into the market. There are also some builders who have their eye on both budget and high performance&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is even a service that sprays a type of sealant into the air while the house is pressurized to seal any little cracks that went unnoticed.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.yahoo.com/advocates-call-utility-lower-proposed-012531440.html&#34;&gt;https://news.yahoo.com/advocates-call-utility-lower-proposed-012531440.html&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, replacing old siding can mean a chance to put batt insulation on the exterior.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.consumeraffairs.com/news/average-heating-bills-could-rise-172-this-winter-092322.html&#34;&gt;https://www.consumeraffairs.com/news/average-heating-bills-could-rise-172-this-winter-092322.html&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Energy_recovery_ventilation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Energy_recovery_ventilation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hwpoo6T3oIA&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hwpoo6T3oIA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fjwjeoLi6X0&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fjwjeoLi6X0&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Ask VCs for Referrals Anyway</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/ask-for-referrals-anyway/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/ask-for-referrals-anyway/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 1.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some years ago I saw a well-known&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; investor on Twitter say, in effect, thatif he decided not to invest in you, don&amp;rsquo;t ask for referrals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From an investor&amp;rsquo;s perspective, this often makes perfect sense. Great investorsplace their money with people they believe will succeed, and perhaps therewere so many red flags the investor couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly recommend the entrepreneurto anyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the investor is talking to the entrepreneur in the first place, however, itprobably means they passed some kind of initial screen: they aren&amp;rsquo;t completelyout there. There are countless stories where investors declined entrepreneursearly on like multiple &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dictionary.com/e/tech-science/decacorn/&#34;&gt;decacorn&lt;/a&gt; company builders Dorsey and Musk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don Valentine did not initially invest in Apple&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Instead, he referredMike Markkula to Steve Jobs. Markkula invested first, then Valentine investedwith Sequoia a year later. Can you imagine if Don Valentine simply brushed them off and said no?I may not be talking about Don Valentine right now, for one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most venture capital firms have an investment thesis that is procured to theirLPs. Angel and seed investors have their own verticals and criteria forinvesting. The narrow scope of these theses precludes at least &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; power law wins.After all, I know of no thesis that is, &amp;ldquo;Invest only in companies that will go public.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have traction on my college social network&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;We are a B2B outfit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have an idea for an electric car.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Oh, we only invest in software.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A great investor will try to help in some way. They may know someone in theirnetwork who has a completely different perspective. If that person invests theycan turn around and reason with the first investor, or the first investor canstill have a way in to the next round. It&amp;rsquo;s also just good business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t quite recall who it was.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_Markkula#Apple&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_Markkula#Apple&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Phone is Still the Best Way to Order Pizza</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/phone-is-still-the-best-way-to-order-pizza/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/phone-is-still-the-best-way-to-order-pizza/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 0.9&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin:auto;text-align:center&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/img/pizzanet.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ordering Pizza in The Net&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When ordering pizza for pickup, there is no easier way to do it than usinga phone. On average, it takes no more than 20 seconds:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dial number&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Say: &amp;ldquo;Large Pizza for Pickup&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hear: &amp;ldquo;OK. 15-20 minutes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many, many websites and apps that partner with local pizza shops.Often these apps require you to sign up or add excess information. Why isone required to put in first name, last name, phone, email, and address whenphone number and first name is all that&amp;rsquo;s required when calling?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s worse is that almost all of these apps require you to &amp;ldquo;sign up.&amp;rdquo; This isone of those situations where signing up is irrelevant, just like with mostmobile apps&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In theory I should be able to autocomplete first name andphone number (maybe credit card&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) and voilà my pizza is in queue. Signing upfor yet-another-food-service-app is a turn off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That technology is causing &lt;em&gt;more friction&lt;/em&gt; than less isn&amp;rsquo;tsurprising. It seems recently that a lot of technology does this. An obviousexample is captcha. We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have hilarious coffee drinking robotcommercials without it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If only the solution were so simple as to build an app that only required firstname and phone number (and dumped that info or just store it in localstorage).The biggest issue of course is getting the menu items into the system. Maybethat&amp;rsquo;s not even necessary. Why not just have an image of a menu and a box whereyou type the order. &amp;ldquo;Extra large pizza, half green peppers and onions, halfextra cheese.&amp;rdquo; Already this system feels like it would in the worst case &lt;em&gt;match&lt;/em&gt;a phone call, but probably cut that time in half &amp;ndash; especially if utilizinglocalstorage. Maybe one day technology can play a role in improving userexperience rather than destroying it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mobile apps can create unique device identifiers, and on iOS they canalso leverage iCloud to store information when moving to new devices.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be necessary, but if for some reason people are submittingfake pizza requests I guess it could be required. People still use cash;something I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing recently as a mechanism for budgeting.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>New Blogging Paradigm: Drafts</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/new-blogging-paradigm/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/new-blogging-paradigm/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges for blogging consistently is finding the time to do itand make good posts. Posts like &amp;ldquo;Who is Satoshi&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;YC Bookmarklet&amp;rdquo; weresimple enough to knock out, so I did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For some time I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to write about in depth topics like self-drivingcars. This is what I&amp;rsquo;ll post next; and while I try to keep a positive vibeon this blog, that next post will be rather critical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to accomplish this, instead of spending a lot of time crafting a blogpost, I will post drafts and revise them. Each post will start at 0.1 and maybeone day it&amp;rsquo;ll reach 1.0.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Who Is Satoshi Nakamoto?</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/who-is-satoshi-nakamoto/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/who-is-satoshi-nakamoto/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The mystery surrounding the identity of Satoshi Nakamoto, creator of Bitcoin,has been entertaining and somewhat frustrating to observe. When that reporterfound a random guy with the name Nakamoto and turned his life upside down, it wasprobably peak &amp;ldquo;we have no idea who this is&amp;rdquo; and yet it is still frustrating to seefrom time to time bright people say, &amp;ldquo;Aha! It is x!&amp;rdquo; with weak evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Satoshi wanted to stay anonymous, and for good reason. If Bitcoin worked,everyone would be after him&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Personally I didn&amp;rsquo;t adopt Bitcoin soonerout of fear of alternative money laws in the US, so imagine creating analternative money! Then, as it grows more successful, the early miningactivity attributed to Satoshi is worth enough to be competitive with thewealthiest individuals in the world. The wealthiest people have &amp;ldquo;security teams.&amp;rdquo;Satoshi, I guarantee, does not have nor want a security team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago I myself was curious so I looked at the genesis of Bitcoin.Based on that story I chose one person and compared that person&amp;rsquo;s code withthe code that Satoshi Nakamoto initially distributed. Next I checked thatperson&amp;rsquo;s writing with Satoshi&amp;rsquo;s writing. The code and writing were verysimilar. The two people&amp;rsquo;s characters were similar. What was different? Well,if you were going to try to conceal your identity you&amp;rsquo;d want good opsec butyou&amp;rsquo;d also want to be good at counterintelligence. Since Satoshi has fooledalmost everyone&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d say he did those things well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t disclose who I think Satoshi is directly. What&amp;rsquo;s the point ofunveiling who it is? If the person wants others to know directly that he isSatoshi then he will do so. In fact, I think one day he may. Here I will onlymake three claims: Satoshi is one person, he is still alive, and he identifiesas &amp;ldquo;he.&amp;rdquo; I was wrong in my estimation of the identity of Startup L Jackson&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;so certainly I could be wrong about Satoshi. But for fun here is a hash of aunique sentence stating his identity:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ae5822f1add18cf25046267de7ede6fea25a512ce06b3d51dbafbcf3e2d7ed7b/512256&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m making a claim on gender here.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amusingly, Gwern touches on it in confusion.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a few randos who make claims, but without evidence.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought it was Hunter Walk, but to be fair I didn&amp;rsquo;t read through theirsource code. Also a bit different circumstance: SLJ was a persona created byThompson and Satoshi merely applies techniques to conceal true identity.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The Curious Case of the Y Combinator Bookmarklet</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/the-curious-case-of-the-ycombinator-bookmarklet/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/the-curious-case-of-the-ycombinator-bookmarklet/</guid>
       <description>&lt;div style=&#34;margin:auto;text-align:center;margin:10px;&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/img/bookmarklet.png&#34; alt=&#34;YC Bookmarklet Page&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I frequent the /new page of Hacker News, usually to find interesting articlesthat were missed by the masses&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In recent years I noticed that people weresubmitting &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&#34;&gt;Y Combinator Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;at least several times a week. From time to time, this would get a small number of upvotes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a while I started wondering why people were submitting this so frequently.Reviewing the bookmarklet page, it suddenly became clear&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Logged-in HN users were &lt;em&gt;clicking thelink which would then submit the bookmarklet page itself to Hacker News&lt;/em&gt;. Atsome point these links were simply automatically marked dead whenever submitted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin:auto;text-align:center;margin:10px;&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/img/deadlink.png&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;HN &#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, there is a better (and simple) solution! Just add javascript to preventthe default behavior. The yellow highlighted text below shows the change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin:auto;text-align:center;margin:10px;&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/img/jssolution.png&#34; alt=&#34;YC Bookmarklet Solution&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This allows users to drag the bookmarklet to their toolbar while preventing themfrom accidentally submitting to HN. An ancillary benefit is that, due to how YCtitles their pages, it will no longer be known as &amp;ldquo;Y Combinator Bookmarklet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This seems to be a problem with HN. First, there should be a preferencewhere landing on /new is the default. Second &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure the solution &amp;ndash;there should be a way to allow for long-form articles because they rarelyif ever make it to the front page.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Worry not, I did not click the link!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>There Should Be More Mergers</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/there-should-be-more-mergers/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/there-should-be-more-mergers/</guid>
       <description>&lt;div style=&#34;margin:auto;text-align:center&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/img/muskthielxpaypal.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thiel and Musk&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In February 2000, Peter Thiel and Elon Musk met at a cafe on University Avenue in Palo Alto to discuss merging Confinity and X.com, their respective companies. Here is how Thiel tells it in &lt;em&gt;Zero to One&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t beat a rival, it may be better to merge. By late 1999, we were in an all out war&amp;hellip; the focus was defeating X.com. In February 2000, Elon and I were more scared about a rapidly inflating tech bubble than we were about each other: a financial crash would ruin us both before we could finish our fight. Sometimes you do have to fight. Where that&amp;rsquo;s true, you should fight and win. There is no middle ground.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;PayPal went on to become a powerful company that today has a market cap of $140 billion. We&amp;rsquo;ll never know what would have happened if Thiel and Musk hadn&amp;rsquo;t agreed on a 50/50 merger. There is a realm of possibility including the unspoken idea that both companies survived and competition drove innovation &amp;ndash; something to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, I&amp;rsquo;m surprised that there aren&amp;rsquo;t more mergers of the same kind. Not paltry acquihires, but rather taking two companies that are otherwise forces with strong teams that would mesh well together.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s possible to object with a claim that maybe a weaker company ought to die out; however, we continue to see Y Combinator fund competitors who don&amp;rsquo;t seem to come to the realization that merging is an option. Y Combinator doesn&amp;rsquo;t fund ideas, it funds founders, and so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow that &amp;ldquo;the weak die out&amp;rdquo; unless Y Combinator was mistaken in their assessment of accepting founders into the accelerator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest examples of this that comes to mind is Balanced Payments, which launched in 2012 a couple years after Stripe. One of the distinguished features of Balanced was an API that allowed developers to integrate marketplaces. Stripe eventually added this feature, but Balanced was reportedly processing $370 million a year in early 2014.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In 2015 Balanced shut down, and Stripe&amp;rsquo;s co-founder Patrick Collison called it &amp;ldquo;bittersweet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that Balanced and Stripe are both Y Combinator companies. Presumably they each had equal access to the resources and advice Y Combinator provides. Without knowing the details of the shut down, it seems odd that the company wouldn&amp;rsquo;t merge with Stripe. Were they drowning in lawsuits? The value of the merger wouldn&amp;rsquo;t exceed the cost of merging? Stripe&amp;rsquo;s valuation dwarfed Balanced&amp;rsquo;s?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Y Combinator seems to be the perfect place for mergers. Every winter for the past three winters, Y Combinator has funded a podcasting company. In winter 2017, Breaker. In winter 2018, The Podcast App. And in winter 2019, Brew. TechCrunch even makes a note of this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The accelerator still admits many international copycats of U.S. successes, and YC is also repeating itself a bit. The Podcast App pitched the exact same product and strategy as Breaker, which debuted at YC exactly a year ago.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, great! Admit them. Advise them. Shower them with resources. But why not suggest a merger at some point? Is there room for 3 podcasting apps? In addition to these there is Stitcher, Marco Arment&amp;rsquo;s Overcast, and the native Podcast app (on iOS at least). So many apps in such a small market is inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One more instance of two Y Combinator companies that would be fit for merging are Yoshi and YourMechanic. YourMechanic started out with a bang; they built something people wanted and had some excellent blog posts which marketed their product, but somehow the leadership disappeared and the company appears to have gone sideways. Yoshi started out with fuel delivery straight to your vehicle, but quickly encroached on YourMechanic&amp;rsquo;s market. It seemed obvious in recent years that these companies combine forces and merge. Instead of a single, efficient mobile mechanic workforce in the Bay Area, for example, there are two workforces and the overhead and marketing costs that go with them yielding less margin for profit (if any!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know whether mergers in any of these instances are a good idea without knowing the details of the companies and the cap tables that go with them. But what&amp;rsquo;s surprising is that we rarely &amp;ndash; if ever &amp;ndash; see a TechCrunch headline announcing that two companies have joined forces. It&amp;rsquo;s even more surprising that we don&amp;rsquo;t see this from Y Combinator given the prevalance of companies they fund in similar markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paraphrased from &lt;em&gt;Zero to One&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, as noted by Thiel in &lt;em&gt;Zero to One&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; Lechvin in &lt;em&gt;Founders at Work&lt;/em&gt; the X-Confinity merger wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best meshing of teams but somehow was good enough to succeed&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/16/balanced-marketplace-payments/&#34;&gt;http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/16/balanced-marketplace-payments/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9200145&#34;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9200145&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/20/these-are-the-64-startups-unveiled-at-y-combinator-w18-demo-day-2/&#34;&gt;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/20/these-are-the-64-startups-unveiled-at-y-combinator-w18-demo-day-2/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>&#34;How Do You Know?&#34;</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/how-do-you-know/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/how-do-you-know/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;In spring of 2017 I was about to move from San Francisco down the peninsula. I had just decided to pause an ambitious side project that attempted to further unsupervised machine learning by automating clustering and instead turn my attention to another project dealing with art&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Y Combinator had announced their first startup school; I applied and was able to join a group of other entrepreneurial types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My art project&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; was going to sell physical art. I had developed an app that enabled people to browse and buy artworks with Stripe. Sounds prosaic but there was an angle of course. Even so, this endeavor was unfortunately not a sit-behind-the-screen and dominate&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; type of project like my ambitious unsupervised machine learning project. It required that I go talk with customers and artists. 😱&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took time, but at the very least I was able to start emailing artists via a yearly Bay Area art event that produces a magazine with all of the participants&amp;rsquo;s contact info. I had a pretty good success rate and set up a meeting with one artist, with another meeting on the way. Not only was I making progress, but also discovered that when you tell artists that you want to sell their work, some want to hear more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point it was about 4 or 5 weeks in, and things were moving too slowly. Yes, it is important to &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/ds.html&#34;&gt;Do Things That Don&amp;rsquo;t Scale&lt;/a&gt; but I was treating this like it was Y Combinator&amp;rsquo;s actual program and if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to show by presentation day, why bother?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I pivoted to another iOS app. This one leveraged the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lob.com&#34;&gt;Lob&lt;/a&gt; printing API to produce post cards with artwork on it. The hypothesis was that people would want to send a postcard with artwork from the location they traveled to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the weekly meeting, the group lead Aaron Glazer, CEO of &lt;a href=&#34;https://taplytics.com&#34;&gt;Taplytics&lt;/a&gt;, had a guest from his former YC Group. We were discussing what was holding us back, and my contribution usually went like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am thinking about trying to sell this concept to real estate agents to thank clients they&amp;rsquo;ve worked with. But I don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;d want it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This may seem dumb, dear reader, but I believe a lot of people suffer from this fallacy. You find a reason why it won&amp;rsquo;t work. &lt;em&gt;Disappearing photos would be great! But that won&amp;rsquo;t work because you can always take a photo of the photo&lt;/em&gt; or perhaps the more familiar &lt;em&gt;Dropbox is something that could be trivially built with rsync and big tech solutions will be pervasive soon enough&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So during this meeting halfway through startup school these guys asked me: &lt;em&gt;How do you know?&lt;/em&gt; And they didn&amp;rsquo;t just say it once. Every time I made an assertion they would ask me, &amp;ldquo;How do you know?&amp;rdquo; There is only one way to know whether something will work, and that is to test the market. You needn&amp;rsquo;t build anything! You could. You could build a prototype. You could produce a video like Drew Houston did with Dropbox. But if you have any assertion without evidence to back it up, you may as well trash it. &lt;em&gt;God doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/em&gt; Is that so? How do you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Likewise, I didn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; whether real estate agents would be interested in artwork postcards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that call I did not follow up with real estate agents because I decided to pivot to augmented reality. But the lesson stuck with me. It is important to ask questions like whether it is the right time and what is the distribution strategy&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to make any assumptions without data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard people talk about eliminating items from idea lists, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never heard advice on how to do that. Consider how awful the idea of AirBnB was. Paul Graham tried to convince AirBnB to change their idea!&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Probably what made it work was Michael Seibel&amp;rsquo;s advice to leverage Craigslist on both the supply and demand side as a distribution strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whenever there is an idea I&amp;rsquo;m unsure of, it is now easy to think &lt;em&gt;How do I know?&lt;/em&gt; If it is something reason would easily talk me out of like an AirBnB concept, I try to get some data. A handful of data points or a few posts on forums is not enough, just as it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be enough in a scientific setting. And as with science, I should at least be able to walk away from the experiment learning something new.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unsupervised machine learning to art? Yes, quite a leap.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not really a startup as there was no growth, right?&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paul Graham may argue that you have to talk with customers either way. But a distribution strategy like that of YouTube (leveraging MySpace) or PayPal (leveraging EBay) did not mean having to arrange meetings with people, and in the case of PayPal the customer who sparked their genius emailed &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Atheism makes no sense unless you are claiming that there is no god in the same way that people claim that there is a god. You can participate in innumerable sophistry contests, but there&amp;rsquo;s no way you can win every time. Just because it &lt;em&gt;seems&lt;/em&gt; like there is no god doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it so!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are perhaps the two most important questions for a startup. It&amp;rsquo;s ok to be a bit early if you can weather it (for example, AR industry is probably going to proliferate when Apple launches glasses in a year or so). Distribution is key for growth.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/paulg/status/1131337639540477954&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/paulg/status/1131337639540477954&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>How I Use Streaming Services</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/how-i-use-streaming-services/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/how-i-use-streaming-services/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Participating in the transition from Blockbuster through Netflix online streaming service was an interesting lesson in change of market dynamics. Netflix realized you could be cost effective at sending DVDs through the mail, while Blockbuster snoozed assuming people would browse in store forever. Sure, browsing in real life is an experience, but it was also something of an annoyance for similar reasons why Amazon was successful&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a while, around 2012 or so, it seemed like Netflix and streaming were the future. But it, too, has had difficulty negotiating deals for desired content with the competition heating up from other services such as Amazon and HBO. Turning to Hollywood to create original content, it seemed like it was off to a good start with the series &lt;em&gt;House of Cards&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But as A-list content dwindled, the pressure was on. Netflix had to produce more original content and it tried to hype up shows like &lt;em&gt;Marco Polo&lt;/em&gt; which ended in failure. Shows like &lt;em&gt;Orange is the New Black&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Narcos&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; helped, but rising subscriber costs contributed to its struggle&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see any recently widely talked about content as they ramp up efforts to try to see what sticks&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many people already had Amazon Prime when they launched Amazon Prime Video. Amazon has also had mediocre success with original content. &lt;em&gt;Jack Ryan&lt;/em&gt; is probably the most talked about, but Amazon, too, has a lengthy list of never-heard-of-this-before original content&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another popular streaming service is HBO Now, which has been able to leverage its A-list content from the cable service with clout frequently advertised by hotels everywhere, HBO. Most well known content-wise here is &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; but has done well with newer series such as &lt;em&gt;Westworld&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Succession&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;HBO Now is actually how I developed my current viewing habits. When it was launched I subscribed to the service just to watch &lt;em&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/em&gt; and then promptly canceled. An ancillary benefit was access to all the A-list content for the month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started doing this around 2015 or 2016, and fast-forward to 2018 when Amazon Prime was due to be renewed. Amazon had just increased the price for a Prime membership, and the benefits were questionable. Shortly after declining to renew Amazon Prime, I also axed Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t reactivated any of these services since, but I know the desirable content has started to queue up. &lt;em&gt;Jack Ryan&lt;/em&gt; was indeed a worthy series. So at some point, just like HBO Now, I&amp;rsquo;ll spin up a Prime Video membership for the month before canceling. This will happen with Netflix as well. Ideally I&amp;rsquo;d subscribe to a service one month and cascade other services in subsequent months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An exception here is Disney Plus. The content, at present, seems to be so good that it will be worth it to just pay for the service month to month without giving it much thought. Disney Plus is also interesting because one of Netflix&amp;rsquo;s pillars is children&amp;rsquo;s content. Imagine busy parents that need an hour a day and let their kids have some screen time. Would they prefer to just pay $10 a month for Netflix or risk subjecting their kids to content from randos on Youtube&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end it may seem rather miserly to forgo a whole $360&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; a year on content and services that could prove beneficial in situations like being stuck in an airport or on a long car ride. $330, however, is a lot of money for most people. You could go out to a nice dinner for two a few times over, or buy a nicer car, or contribute that money to Watsi&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. But I think it speaks more about how the business model of streaming services is broken. It&amp;rsquo;s a commodity&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the only reason to have the service is if you truly like content that hasn&amp;rsquo;t entered the zeitgeist like &lt;em&gt;House of Cards&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;, or if you really feel compelled to have water cooler conversations about the latest episode on Monday morning. Disney Plus will be an interesting service to follow. It seems like it has the hallmark of success with so much A-list content, and if you&amp;rsquo;ve been paying attention &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update: I forgot I had wanted to contrast video streaming with music services (I wrote this post quickly because otherwise I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have written anything). Music services like Spotify and Apple Music are perfect for platform lock-in. It makes sense to pay $10-$15 a month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon took the pain away of not finding the book you want in bookstores. Similarly, Netflix took the pain away of settling for some B-list movie because there were no other options in the Blockbuster you were browsing.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/greatspeculations/2019/07/19/netflixs-original-content-strategy-is-failing/&#34;&gt;https://www.forbes.com/sites/greatspeculations/2019/07/19/netflixs-original-content-strategy-is-failing/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_original_programs_distributed_by_Netflix&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_original_programs_distributed_by_Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_original_programs_distributed_by_Amazon&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_original_programs_distributed_by_Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theoutline.com/post/1239/youtube-has-a-fake-peppa-pig-problem&#34;&gt;https://theoutline.com/post/1239/youtube-has-a-fake-peppa-pig-problem&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Services vary from $8 for standalone Amazon Video to $15 for HBO Now, but let&amp;rsquo;s just say the services on average are around $10, and for three services for 12 months it is around $360.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do it! Right now! &lt;a href=&#34;https://watsi.org&#34;&gt;https://watsi.org&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a commodity in the sense that people aren&amp;rsquo;t loyal to a service (except perhaps Disney Plus!) but instead just want to &amp;ldquo;watch something.&amp;rdquo;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>You Can&#39;t Top Bitcoin</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/you-cant-top-bitcoin/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/you-cant-top-bitcoin/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I consider myself a crypto altruist; I don&amp;rsquo;t subscribe to any sort of maximalism of any cryptocurrency. I want to see everyone have access to this technology regardless of the particular implementation, so long as it is entirely open source and has been peer reviewed by computer scientists&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I began studying cryptocurrencies a few years ago, I recognized that they were flawed. They require untold amounts of data to store the timechain, and perhaps worse the computing power and lengthy confirmation time make monetary transactions as we know them impossible. Digging through research papers, I learned how challenging of a problem it was to ensure speed, security, and decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seemed like Bitcoin &amp;ndash; and especially Ethereum &amp;ndash; were unsustainable in terms of space and computing power required, not to mention they practically violate the ethos of a decentralized money system with mining being highly concentrated&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. To me, it seemed the path forward was something that worked well on mobile devices, or else how would cryptocurrency be adopted by billions of people? Since then a few solutions have surfaced that intend to work on mobile or by leveraging trusted computing centers in conjunction with a mobile solution. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if any of these will ultimately succeed, but few if any people in the crypto community seem to support them. For reference, &lt;a href=&#34;https://a16zcrypto.com/2019/04/celo/&#34;&gt;Celo&lt;/a&gt; is approximately what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about here, if it works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fred Wilson said a couple years ago that he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if Ethereum surpassed Bitcoin in value&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This makes sense as Ethereum has the potential for people to develop applications on the platform that grow in value. Ethereum has an excellent ecosystem and the tooling is fantastic&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It is likely Ethereum will end up being of some non-trivial value in 10 years because of the wealth created via Ethereum apps. I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt, however, that there will be plenty of competition. Programmers are unfortunately fickle. Ruby on Rails was the hottest thing 10 years ago, and now we have Go, Rust, Swift, Node, and dozens of frameworks that associate with those&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a Magic the Gathering is built on Tezos or EOS or Ethereum, &amp;amp;c. It has a lot of followers that know all about the cards and play the game, creating value. A friend sends a card (token) to my wallet as a gift. Thank you, but I&amp;rsquo;m not into Magic the Gathering. My wallet tells me it is worth $250 &amp;ndash; awesome! Do I put it up for sale, hold on to it, or buy more Magic cards in hopes they will be worth even more one day? As a gift I may hold on to it, at least for some time. But likely I&amp;rsquo;ll sell it or trade it for something I am more familiar with. Cash? Gold? Those things are minted in central banks and possibly mined in asteroids&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. If I want to buy a used Apple Watch or I want jewlery, sure. Instead maybe I trade it for a token that is pegged to a stock with solid fundamentals, or maybe I put it in a store of value that has proven historically to increase in value over the long term. Those seem immensely easier options. And if you are someone who dismisses crypto, read &lt;em&gt;Green Eggs and Ham&lt;/em&gt; and then try donating to &lt;a href=&#34;https://watsi.org/faq#does-watsi-accept-bitcoin-donations&#34;&gt;Watsi&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/donate/cryptocurrency/&#34;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt; with it; less friction always wins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is a store of value. It has brand recognition. The social challenge of overcoming its dominance is like campaigning Kay Jewelers to be more valuable than &lt;a href=&#34;https://qz.com/174122/tiffanys-blue-boxes-are-red-hot-on-the-black-market/&#34;&gt;Tiffany&lt;/a&gt;. Fork market caps pale to Bitcoin, and even if they succeeded you&amp;rsquo;d still own it. Exceptional value is also Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s biggest problem. Lightning was designed to enable instantaneous low fee transactions, but you need to stake Bitcoin. As an appreciating asset why stake it? People who were early to Bitcoin and have spent it might casually participate, but the users being onboarded today are unlikely to do this. In the US there are tax implications which is a huge turnoff to spending an appreciating asset like Bitcoin. This is just the reality. Perhaps legislation changes the landscape here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The development that has me convinced Bitcoin will continue to be a store of value and the dominant of all cryptocurrencies is the rise of stable coins&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Stable coins are ideally pegged to the US Dollar, and while there are small fluctuations I suspect there will soon be some kind of exemption for taxes in the US. Stable coins will be used for day to day transactions. No rational person is going to want to trade their Bitcoin if they think it is going to continue to rise in value!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People will transact daily in stable coins, they will buy virtual goods on Ethereum and it will wax and wane in value, new networks will emerge and also wax and wane, but Bitcoin will remain the strongest store of value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;By &amp;ldquo;computer scientists&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t mean people who hold degrees necessarily, but anyone who is capable of building a blockchain from scratch. A consensus on the merits of the technology is what matters, not nitpicking.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I realize this is a contested point. Ideally you&amp;rsquo;d have x nodes and 1/x nodes odds of earning a reward, but I digress.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;People misquote him as saying &amp;ldquo;he thinks it will&amp;rdquo; when in fact he said he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I built Glossy.cards, an ERC721 creator to sell collectibles for free, using Golang with the assistance of geth, web3, Metamask, Infura. (Sure, infura is a crutch, but Ethereum is still in development). Was impressed so much production-ready infrastructure was built in such a short time.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would be great if y&amp;rsquo;all just decided on one language for professional purposes and used the rest for hobby. I vote for a LISP; Clojure is ok I guess. Risp? Maybe something that supports tail call optimization.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seems like science fiction, but so does decelerating rockets and landing them on small pads in a rough ocean.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not lost on me that Bitcoin could one day be measured in terms of stable coins which themselves will have intrinsic value.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Grocery &amp; Meal Delivery</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/grocery-and-meal-delivery/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/grocery-and-meal-delivery/</guid>
       <description>&lt;section data-field=&#34;body&#34; class=&#34;e-content&#34;&gt;&lt;section name=&#34;295a&#34; class=&#34;section section--body section--first section--last&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;section-divider&#34;&gt;&lt;hr class=&#34;section-divider&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;section-content&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&#34;&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;6655&#34; id=&#34;6655&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&#34;&gt;I still go to the grocery store in part for the experience and the discovery process. Often times, however, I’ve wished I could just skip the store and have the groceries appear within a day. The problem with that is then I need to sign up for some delivery service and still spend time paging through an app to find dozens of necessities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure name=&#34;a658&#34; id=&#34;a658&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--figure graf--iframe graf-after--p&#34;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BenedictEvans/status/640220835119173633&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;9c0d&#34; id=&#34;9c0d&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&#34;&gt;I have tried a few services including Instacart and Amazon Now, and both worked out fine except for the economics. On top of the cost of groceries is an added percentage, fee, and tip. What’s hard for me to understand is why these companies aren’t able to tap into the fixed costs of a traditional supermarket. While supermarket net margins tends to be around &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fmi.org/research-resources/supermarket-facts&#34; data-href=&#34;http://www.fmi.org/research-resources/supermarket-facts&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1.7%&lt;/a&gt;, gross margins are in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://csimarket.com/Industry/industry_Profitability_Ratios.php?ind=1305&#34; data-href=&#34;http://csimarket.com/Industry/industry_Profitability_Ratios.php?ind=1305&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20% range&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure name=&#34;c06f&#34; id=&#34;c06f&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--figure graf-after--p&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 623px; max-height: 603px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;aspectRatioPlaceholder-fill&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;graf-image&#34; data-image-id=&#34;1*wRHTDnH0Vl6E89NtUGE_Yg.png&#34; data-width=&#34;623&#34; data-height=&#34;603&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*wRHTDnH0Vl6E89NtUGE_Yg.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are over a dozen Safeway supermarket stores in San Francisco&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;4173&#34; id=&#34;4173&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&#34;&gt;Considering the costs of real estate, utilities, employees, logistics, and insurance, it seems there should be enough for this service:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&#34;postList&#34;&gt;&lt;li name=&#34;7fcb&#34; id=&#34;7fcb&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--li graf-after--p&#34;&gt;Instead of 15 stores, situate 3 warehouses in the vicinity of Excelsior, Dogpatch, and Inner Sunset (i.e. highways and center of mass)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name=&#34;a40a&#34; id=&#34;a40a&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--li graf-after--li&#34;&gt;Automate the warehouses so that pallets come off the trucks from supplier and are robotically transported to their row and bin; individual items are robotically retrieved to fill a shopping bag&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name=&#34;0848&#34; id=&#34;0848&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--li graf-after--li&#34;&gt;The store employees are now delivery drivers. Bags are robotically loaded into the vans so the driver just has to get in and follow an efficient route and unload the bags to homes, offices, car trunks, &amp;amp;c.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;e131&#34; id=&#34;e131&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--li&#34;&gt;The above seems reasonably doable, so I wonder why no one does it. Even if certain aspects aren’t automated from the start, it can be done over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;c855&#34; id=&#34;c855&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--p&#34;&gt;What about perishable items? I think instead of bags reusable crates could be used with built in icepack. Since I consistently demolish large boxes from Amazon I’m not sure why they haven’t gone reusable yet, though with their own fleet it seems likely to be on their roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;5899&#34; id=&#34;5899&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--p&#34;&gt;What about stolen groceries? I think stolen groceries would be about as likely as stolen Amazon packages. Some neighborhoods may be more susceptible, especially in San Francisco, so having items delivered to work or a car trunk may be a solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;3290&#34; id=&#34;3290&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&#34;&gt;Lastly, if the vision weren’t already over the top, I think combining groceries with a “chef meal” service makes sense. That is, you get chopped vegetables and other ingredients along with a recipe so you can make a fancy dinner with ease. Maybe this would be a premium service, but hopefully far cheaper than current services with this offering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Hyperloop May Create New Cities</title>
       <link>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/hyperloop-may-create-new-cities/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://dan.bulwinkle.net/blog/hyperloop-may-create-new-cities/</guid>
       <description>&lt;section name=&#34;edc2&#34; class=&#34;section section--body section--first section--last&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;section-divider&#34;&gt;&lt;hr class=&#34;section-divider&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;section-content&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&#34;&gt;&lt;h4 name=&#34;8d39&#34; id=&#34;8d39&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--h4 graf-after--h3 graf--subtitle&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure name=&#34;4912&#34; id=&#34;4912&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--figure graf-after--h4&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 700px; max-height: 394px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;aspectRatioPlaceholder-fill&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;graf-image&#34; data-image-id=&#34;1*wf12DR56qTrY3C7uzVKfBQ.jpeg&#34; data-width=&#34;1320&#34; data-height=&#34;743&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*wf12DR56qTrY3C7uzVKfBQ.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hyperloop concept from the original SpaceX white paper.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;aade&#34; id=&#34;aade&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&#34;&gt;Were I to create a hyperloop company I may call it R-Loop to emphasize keeping out the hype. If I was lucky maybe one day it would be known simply as “The R” just as elevated trains in Philly and Chicago are known as “The El.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;b459&#34; id=&#34;b459&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--p&#34;&gt;It’s been just a couple years since two major hyperloop companies have been in existence and the outlook is dubious. Hyperloop One had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-08-15/how-hyperloop-one-went-off-the-rails&#34; data-href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-08-15/how-hyperloop-one-went-off-the-rails&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cofounder breakup&lt;/a&gt; which is often an ominous sign in startups, and there hasn’t been &lt;a href=&#34;http://hyperlooptransp.com/#!/updates&#34; data-href=&#34;http://hyperlooptransp.com/#!/updates&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;much news&lt;/a&gt; of the other company. Even if these companies don’t succeed someone will take the opportunity and figure out how to execute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;e8e5&#34; id=&#34;e8e5&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--p&#34;&gt;In a place like the Bay Area, the hyperloop could mean an alternative to local governments who &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bizjournals.com/sanfrancisco/blog/real-estate/2016/06/brisbane-officials-want-zero-housing-on-baylands.html&#34; data-href=&#34;http://www.bizjournals.com/sanfrancisco/blog/real-estate/2016/06/brisbane-officials-want-zero-housing-on-baylands.html&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;refuse&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mercurynews.com/2016/09/02/palo-alto-seeks-job-housing-balance-in-land-use-plan/&#34; data-href=&#34;http://www.mercurynews.com/2016/09/02/palo-alto-seeks-job-housing-balance-in-land-use-plan/&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;build&lt;/a&gt; new housing. Why commute by car from Berkeley over to San Francisco which could take over 45 minutes each way, when you could hyperloop into San Francisco in 20 to 30 minutes? Even assuming self-driving vehicles eventually earn a comparable time, housing costs are still problematic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure name=&#34;9dcb&#34; id=&#34;9dcb&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--figure graf-after--p&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 593px; max-height: 553px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;aspectRatioPlaceholder-fill&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;graf-image&#34; data-image-id=&#34;1*eEzOvOYa9VPPFI3Gtv8bRQ.png&#34; data-width=&#34;593&#34; data-height=&#34;553&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*eEzOvOYa9VPPFI3Gtv8bRQ.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brisbane, a city adjacent to San Francisco, recently rejected a proposal to &lt;a href=&#34;http://brisbanebaylands.com/plan/&#34; data-href=&#34;http://brisbanebaylands.com/plan/&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;build thousands of new units&lt;/a&gt; on this large plot of land which has two 101 exits and a Caltrain station. Driving through it at night you’d think you were in wine country.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;ec6e&#34; id=&#34;ec6e&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&#34;&gt;I asked my friend who is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.planetizen.com/topschools&#34; data-href=&#34;http://www.planetizen.com/topschools&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;city planner from MIT&lt;/a&gt; what San Francisco could do to relieve the problem. He replied that properties need to stop being used as unoccupied investment vehicles and the city should let loose on high rise construction, particularly in former industrial areas like SoMa, which allows for a compromise to preserve the character of neighborhoods like Noe Valley. So far few Bay Area cities are making efforts to allow for vast new home construction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;e57f&#34; id=&#34;e57f&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--p&#34;&gt;I realized, like many others probably, that hyperloop could solve this problem by connecting San Francisco to more rural areas and building an expandable city there. I ran this idea by my friend who told me newly planned cities almost never succeed, and it is far better to improve existing cities. But you know, Wall Street traders from Wharton and venture capitalists from Stanford and city planners from MIT excel at learning from history; one thing they have in common is they can’t predict the future very well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;a339&#34; id=&#34;a339&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--p&#34;&gt;The kind of effect the hyperloop has on society may be predicted by recalling the effects of new technologies like the railroad or air travel, but history can’t tell us what happens when we have multiple technologies that are only a decade or two old working together. Just as Tesla was able to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-04-07/tesla-says-model-3-pre-orders-surge-to-325-000-in-first-week&#34; data-href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-04-07/tesla-says-model-3-pre-orders-surge-to-325-000-in-first-week&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mark billions in preorders&lt;/a&gt; for the Model III, we could use the Internet to propose a new city for which a hyperloop company has worked out a route. A developer could take preorders for home plans, and the hyperloop company could get to work. Some attrition may occur, but also augmentation once the city becomes a reality. Would people buy a home site unseen? For the current generation of homebuyers the answer may be yes. Everything is bought online today, &lt;a href=&#34;http://shift.com&#34; data-href=&#34;http://shift.com&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;even&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://tesla.com&#34; data-href=&#34;http://tesla.com&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cars&lt;/a&gt;. What is more important is if friends are also buying in the city and how easy it is to get to San Francisco or Portland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;fe3f&#34; id=&#34;fe3f&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--p&#34;&gt;Being in such a new city provides more opportunity. Let’s assume the new city is around Eureka, CA. Someone who lives there decides to leave their San Francisco job for a job in Portland, so their commute goes from 20 minutes to 30 minutes one way. After work on Friday they decide to head to San Francisco to get an &lt;a href=&#34;http://impossiblefoods.com/burger/&#34; data-href=&#34;http://impossiblefoods.com/burger/&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Impossible Burger&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://cockscombsf.com&#34; data-href=&#34;http://cockscombsf.com&#34; class=&#34;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cockscomb&lt;/a&gt; with old friends. No big deal, just a 50 minute hyperloop ride from work and a 20 minute hyperloop ride back home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure name=&#34;0d83&#34; id=&#34;0d83&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--figure graf-after--p&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 427px; max-height: 609px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;aspectRatioPlaceholder-fill&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;graf-image&#34; data-image-id=&#34;1*uFK8cQB0JpOf-b2i8-mXRg.png&#34; data-width=&#34;427&#34; data-height=&#34;609&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*uFK8cQB0JpOf-b2i8-mXRg.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hyperloop could create new cities between San Francisco and Portland.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p name=&#34;d8a9&#34; id=&#34;d8a9&#34; class=&#34;graf graf--p graf-after--figure graf--trailing&#34;&gt;All of this is predicated on a hyperloop company successfully creating the technology and making money. But I think once that happens, public and private sectors will recognize the incredible opportunity and devote resources to seizing it. People will buy land, create crowdfunding campaigns, secure bank loans, new homes and parks will be created, new cafes and businesses will rise, and the quality of life will be among the best.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
 </channel>
</rss>
